(BOMBS EXPLODING)
(SHRIEKING INTENSIFYING)
MAN: Get down!
(JETS ZOOMING)
(SHRIEKING CONTINUES)
Mary!
Get in here.
(GRUNTS)
Visor.
(SHRIEKING CONTINUES)
Ohh!
No!
(SHRIEKING CONTINUES)
(PITCH MODULATING)
Help. I'm burning.
Excuse me.
Hey. Hey.
My arm is on fire.
Thank you very much, sir.
Could you please get me down
from here?
Hold on.
MAN: We wear the armor of
Mithras and the Light.
We are shielded from
all that is harmful.
Hail...
(EXPLOSIONS IN DISTANCE)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Do you mind?
I'm so sorry.
(GRUNTS)
Thank you.
(PINGING, WHIRRING)
It's an A-Class medical.
Looks like he was doing
medical exams
on Mithraic officers
and their families.
MARY: What for?
They were chosen
to go on the ark.
All their identifying
information is on here.
Can these things do
plastic surgery?
Of course.
I'm also proficient in
war wounds, crani...
Okay, shut up.
Yes, sir.
We're about the same build
as these two.
We can get their passes.
If we don't get on the ark,
we're gonna die,
along with everything else
on this planet.
This android is
barely functioning.
I still have 70% capability.
I'll go first.
Okay?
(SIGHS) Okay.
♪♪
Hey.
Now, why don't you go find us
something to eat?
♪♪
CALEB: Is this gonna hurt?
Marginally.
♪♪
This might make you feel better.
Morphine.
♪♪
(GUNSHOT)
(RATS SQUEALING)
♪♪
You are doing really well.
This'll hurt a little bit more.
(GROANS LIGHTLY)
(DEVICE POWERS UP)
Here we go.
(SKIN SIZZLING)
(GROANING)
(SIZZLING CONTINUES)
Fuck!
♪♪
(GROANING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
♪♪
This will graft within two days.
Please do not use soap
or water to clean.
This will be permanent.
(GRUNTING)
♪♪
That didn't hurt a bit.
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHS)
You are next.
It's okay.
More to the back, please.
Okay.
You just gotta breathe.
Just keep breathing.
I'm right here.
♪ Good King Wenceslas
looked out ♪
♪ On the feast of Stephen ♪
(WHIMPERING)
♪ When the snow
lay 'round about ♪
♪ Deep and crisp and even ♪
♪ Brightly shone
the moon that night ♪
Why does He allow us to suffer?
He tests us.
Can you please try
a little harder?
What?
You're gonna have to be more
convincing than that.
He tests us.
We've gone this far.
Can you please commit?
He tests us.
Wasn't so hard,
was it?
Mary?
Albert, where is she?
(CRYING)
Mary?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I hate it.
I like it.
Caleb.
It's Marcus.
(CRYING)
And it's Sue from now on.
No!
We'll get through this.
We wear the armor of Mithras
and the Light.
We are shielded from
all that is harmful.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
This must be it.
(WAVES CRASHING)
(JETS ZOOMING)
(POT BUBBLING)
Show yourselves.
♪♪
We wear the armor of Mithras
and the light.
We are shielded by...
What?
They have a kid.
It says he'll be returned to us
at the boarding area.
Digital pass keys
34, 35, 36.
♪♪
We have a son.
MAN: Sol, guide us with your
brightness and your glory.
You, the all-seeing,
unconquerable light,
may darkness never come.
(COMPUTER PINGING)
(MAN SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
...so that we may serve...
God of the sunset,
Dow, descending immortal.
- Bless my soul.
- ...watches over...
God of the sunset,
low upon the western main.
Dow, descending immortal,
immortal to rise again.
I think that's him.
♪♪
Hi, Paul.
Hello, son.
Hello, Father, Mother.
CLERIC: Captain Drusus.
We took good care of him.
Thank you.
WOMAN: All congregants,
please have your identification
passes ready for inspection.
Come on.
Back in line.
Bye, Paul.
Bye.
♪♪
Welcome,
brothers and sisters.
We will pray.
We will worship.
We will atone for the sins
we committed on Earth.
And when we reach
the Promised Land,
Sol will reward us.
Sol, deliver us
from this ruined world.
♪♪
Hey, you alright?
I'm scared.
It's alright.
It doesn't feel right.
It's gonna be okay.
It's alright. Okay?
♪♪
(DOGS BARKING)
♪ The door that finally opens ♪
♪ With light flooding in ♪
♪ Spilling out on the floor ♪
♪ The core that never was ♪
♪ Now it will be ♪
♪ The bones of
what was there before ♪
♪ Every step, every beat ♪
♪ Every thought, every breath ♪
♪ Everything ♪
♪ Is longing ♪
♪♪
♪ Every wind, every wave ♪
♪ Every sky, every cloud ♪
♪ Every grave ♪
♪ Is longing ♪
♪♪
♪ Pulling you from the sky ♪
♪ Just like love will do ♪
♪♪
(HUMMING)
(HUMMING CONTINUES)
♪♪
(BONE CRACKS)
(ORGANS SQUISHING)
♪♪
(PINGING)
(GASPS)
The internal distress
you're feeling is normal.
You've had a new processor
installed.
Now you need to stay calm
or you're going to undo
all my hard work.
If you want me to remain calm,
Mother,
why did you reactivate me?
Your eyes.
Hmm?
Do they look alright?
What?
My original eyes
had to be removed...
for the sake of the children.
The children?
Yes.
Campion,
and now five more.
They come from
an ark called Heaven.
Don't worry, Father.
We'll get it right this time.
♪♪
(WIND HOWLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
♪♪
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
♪♪
Oh, that's much better.
You said they threatened
to take Campion.
I don't want to talk about it
anymore, Father.
We have much to do,
children to raise.
Go ahead, Father.
Go ahead with what,
Mother?
You can make a joke if you like.
Perhaps later, then.
I sense you're staring at me.
Please stop.
I never lost control.
I just drew on a part of myself
I didn't know existed.
My actions served our
core programming objective.
You have nothing
to be concerned about.
I can't weaponize
without my eyes.
You've destroyed them?
No.
We might need them again later.
So you destroyed me on purpose.
There was no loss of control.
You were the one who
lost control, Father,
when you tried going
against the mission.
And the Mithraic that came here
turned out to be
every bit as vicious
and terrible
as our creator programmed us
to believe.
They tried to kill me
in front of Campion, Father.
Welcome.
♪♪
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
Father!
(CHUCKLES)
Hey.
Come with me.
♪♪
Mother said you broke down,
that she threw your body into
one of the serpent pits.
No, we had a fight.
She deactivated me.
Father, she killed everyone
aboard that ark.
One of the soldiers said that...
♪♪
...she was a Necromancer.
FATHER: You don't have to
be afraid anymore.
She has since disarmed herself.
Is that one of your jokes,
Father?
We have to take charge
before she changes ag...
♪♪
What are you going to
do with them?
How many times did you say
that you wished
we were a family again?
Now we are.
I'm sure you must be nervous
about fitting in with
your new companions.
Just be yourself, Campion.
Stop trying to act like
it didn't happen!
It's okay.
Sol will protect us.
No, he won't.
Come on.
Pray with me.
(WHIMPERING)
We wear the armor...
Shut up.
Sol helps those who
help themselves.
Maybe we can sneak outta here
the next chance we get.
And go where?
We don't know anything
about this planet.
Unless I ask you to speak,
you'd be smart to
keep your mouth shut.
We shouldn't fight
with each other.
We'll never survive if
we fight with each other.
(MOUSE SQUEAKING)
MOTHER: Brought food.
I'm sure you all
must be very hungry.
Come and sit.
Vita, Holly, Tempest,
Paul, Hunter, and Campion.
Careful, it's hot.
Don't, Vita.
Father and I will take care
of you from now on.
But there is no religion
permitted here,
Mithraic or any other kind,
so before we eat,
you will need to
give me your pendants.
These are weights
you no longer need to carry.
Thank you.
What is most important
is that you do not try
and leave the settlement.
I know you're all very curious
about the planet,
but if you run off on your own,
you'll only end up starving,
if you don't freeze
to death first.
Once you've become acclimated,
we'll migrate to
the tropical zone
where survival will be easier,
freeing you to concentrate
on building
a new, peaceful,
atheistic civilization.
(CHUCKLES)
Come on. Eat up.
It's not poison.
(HUMMING)
Campion.
♪♪
Spiria.
(BLOWS)
FATHER: I often replay
my memories of the children.
We need to
make new memories now.
I was wondering, Mother,
have you sufficiently
secured your other eyes?
♪♪
I want us to be able
to trust each other,
but I also hope you will respect
what is mine.
Of course.
♪♪
I'm not hiding them from you,
Father.
I am pleased to hear it.
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
I want things to be
as they were with us.
So do I, Mother.
So do I.
Hmm.
♪♪
They'll help keep us safe.
(SHOVELING)
♪♪
Well?
Has she destroyed her eyes?
If she hasn't,
I say we take them,
throw them down one of the pits,
just to be sure.
I'm taking care of it,
Campion.
Are you sure?
I'm sorry, Father.
I don't mean to
keep questioning you.
Never hesitate to question me,
Campion.
But you have to accept
the answers I give
and have faith that I will
always do what is best for you.
I do, Father.
Why don't you go
and see if you can
help those children feel
a little less afraid?
You think they will like me?
Of course they will like you.
You're a human,
just like they are.
♪♪
You can have these.
They'll keep you warm
while you sleep.
I've never seen kids
as big as you before.
Mother will make you
some special clothes,
just for you.
They're a little stiff
when she first...
When she first makes them,
but they'll soften up
the more you wear them.
Well, that's great news.
Thanks.
Oh,
you are welcome.
(SCOFFS)
So, what happened to Gabin?
How did you know that name?
♪♪
Gabin got sick.
The others, too?
Yes.
(MOUSE SQUEAKING)
It's called a mouse,
isn't it?
Yes, they're actually
born on Earth.
And all of you were born
on Earth, too?
Yes, we're actually 13 years
older than we look.
We were in hibernation,
see?
It's so small.
We don't have any animals
on 22b.
Let him hold it.
Hunter, don't.
♪♪
(SQUEAKING)
(LAUGHING)
You want to keep it?
♪♪
No. Can't.
It... It is yours.
(SQUEAKS)
No, it's alright.
You should have it.
You sure?
Yep.
HUNTER: Your friends
didn't get sick.
She killed them.
She's a Necromancer.
They're built for
mass extermination.
She probably did it
without even knowing it.
If you think that male android's
gonna protect us, forget it.
He's a generic service model.
Necromancers eat those
for breakfast.
You see, androids,
they were built to protect us,
to do our dirty work,
so we can stay pure.
If they had feelings,
they'd be useless.
Have you ever seen how they look
when they don't know
they're being watched?
See, the reason why they don't
want you to believe in Sol
is because they're afraid
of what it's gonna
open your eyes to,
the power it will give you.
Do you want to pray with us?
You know I'm not allowed to.
And neither are you.
If Mother catches you, she'll...
Alright, maybe you could
keep watch, then.
♪♪
TOGETHER: Sol, guide us with
your brightness and your glory.
You, the all-seeing
and unconquerable light.
HUNTER: May darkness never come,
and may the dawn go on forever.
Help us keep our souls pure
that we may serve you.
(HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING)
♪♪
Campion?
What?
He gave it to me.
He was no longer in need of it.
Well, you're old enough to know
what's best.
I don't want you to do those
things with your face anymore.
What things?
The way you look at me.
I know it's not real.
I don't understand.
Yeah,
you probably don't.
Give it to him.
Give it to him!
♪♪
Paul.
Sorry.
Thank you.
Come along.
You need to show them
how it's done.
♪♪
The carbos grow only where
the serpent's bones lay.
That is why we named him
the Giver.
These ones are no good.
It's hard finding
really good ones.
TEMPEST: We're not afraid
of hard work.
We're from military families.
Unlike him.
Hey, I got an IQ of 205,
alright?
If you want me rolling around in
the dirt like slave boy, fine,
but it's a waste of
my intelligence, okay?
205?
Yeah.
Are you the smartest
in the group, then?
Yeah, by far.
What about you?
Are you sure you're not
the smartest of the group?
No, I don't think
I'm smarter than him.
Yeah.
Hmm.
Hunter, come here.
Yeah. Sure.
Yeah.
Alright, now,
listen carefully.
Yeah.
A malfunctioning android,
a Cleric,
and a cat walk into a brothel.
The malfunctioning android
requests
an android whore
with mechanical skills.
The Cleric requests a virgin
with the knowledge of
the Mithraic mysteries.
But the cat... the cat can't
decide what to ask for,
so he turns to the
malfunctioning android
and the Cleric
and asks for suggestions.
The Cleric turns to
the malfunctioning android
and says,
"How is it a cat can speak?"
To which the malfunctioning
android turns and says,
"I am malfunctioning.
None of this is
actually happening.
The cat doesn't exist,
and neither do you."
(SCOFFS) To which the Cleric
then says, "Thank goodness.
For a minute there, I thought
I was losing my mind."
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
You see,
it's a paradox.
I have many jokes tailored for
geniuses like yourself.
This next one also involves
a cat. Yeah, you know what?
Um, I think I'm just gonna, uh,
work with the others.
Yeah. But thanks.
Thanks. Alright.
Now close your eyes.
Close your eyes.
I want you to think back
to a time before
humans gained their sight,
when you were all just blind,
simple organisms,
floating in the vast oceans
of the Earth.
The warmth of the star
drawing you to the surface.
♪♪
(HEART BEATING)
Can you come with me
for a moment?
♪♪
Campion, continue the lesson
until I return, please.
She'll be fine.
No need to worry.
I've taken care of it.
(WIND HOWLING)
I want you to sleep in here
from now on.
You don't have to
work in the fields.
You can do house cleaning.
You need special care,
constant monitoring.
There's too much at stake
to take any chances.
Take chances with what?
You have been given the greatest
gift that can be given.
What's the matter?
Am I scaring you?
No.
It was against my will.
While I was inside
the shared simulation.
The man who did it was able
to wake himself up somehow,
had his way with some of us
while our bodies were
still in hibernation.
There were plans to execute him.
Thanks to you,
he probably died a few days
earlier than scheduled.
I would thank you,
but I was actually looking
forward to watching him die.
He was a Heliodromus,
the second-highest ranking
member of our church.
The thought that there's
something part him
growing inside me...
it makes me want to die.
Then you must not think of him.
Think only of the child.
The child is innocent.
I will help you.
We'll do this together.
♪♪
Knock, knock.
Who's there?
Punch.
Punch who?
Punch line,
but I must warn you
I am a bit of a disappointment.
Not bad.
The little one might like it.
Save that one.
Knock, knock.
(GRUMBLING SOUND)
Who's there?
(BONES CLATTER)
(CREATURE HISSES)
(CREATURE GROANS)
♪♪
Sleep now.
(CREATURE GROANS)
Tell me you didn't destroy them.
Campion.
I'll handle this,
Mother.
Mother,
I'll handle this.
♪♪
Tell me where they are.
Campion!
No. You said you would
deal with it, but you didn't.
You didn't do anything!
There are intruders
inside the perimeter.
We are in danger!
Tell me where they are, Campion!
No.
Tell me, Campion.
Tell me, Campion!
♪♪
Stay back!
(CREATURE CHITTERING)
♪♪
(SCREAMS)
(SHRIEKING)
(CREATURE SQUEALING)
(SCREAMS)
(DISTORTED VOICE)
Don't look at me, Tempest.
Go back to the barracks.
♪♪
I think they're gone now,
Mother.
You should cycle down now,
(POWERING DOWN)
♪♪
Animals of some kind.
We've been here for 12 years.
How could we just be
encountering them now?
A good question.
I would study their remains,
if you left any.
I thought we knew this region
and all its dangers,
but we don't.
Thank you, Father.
For what, Mother?
For not taking my eyes.
♪♪
(CREATURES PANTING, SNIFFING)
MAN: These things settled
around here somewhere.
(DEVICE PINGING)
Here.
♪♪
- Come on.
- That's it!
♪♪
One, two, three.